The constant thud underneath your feet,
الدوي المتواصل لقدميك،
the constrained space,
و المساحة المقيدة،
and the monotony of going nowhere fast.
ورتابة السير إلى اللامكان بسرعة.
It feels like hours have gone by, but it's only been eleven minutes,
إنها تشعرك بأن ساعات قد انقضت، إلا أنها كانت إحدى عشرة دقيقة فقط.
and you wonder,
وقد تتساءل:
"Why am I torturing myself?
"لماذا أقوم بتعذيب نفسي؟"
This thing has got to be considered a cruel and unusual punishment."
لابد أن هذا الشيء الذي أقوم به عقوبة قاسية وغير اعتيادية."
Actually, that's exactly what it is, or was.
في الواقع، هذا هو بالضبط ما هو عليه الأمر، أو ما كان عليه.
You see, in the 1800s,
كما ترى، خلال القرن التاسع عشر،
treadmills were created to punish English prisoners.
تم إنشاء المشايات لمعاقبة السجناء الإنكليز.
At the time, the English prison system was abysmally bad.
في ذلك الوقت، كان نظام السجون الإنجليزية سيئًا إلى حد بعيد.
Execution and deportation were often the punishments of choice,
كانت عقوبتا الإعدام والنفي في كثير من الأحيان هما المطبقتين،
and those who were locked away faced hours of solitude in filthy cells.
وأولئك الذين يُحبسون، يقضون ساعات من العزلة في زنازين قذرة.
So social movements led by religious groups, philanthropies,
مما دفع الحركات الاجتماعية بقيادة الجماعات الدينية،والجمعيات الخيرية،
and celebrities, like Charles Dickens,
والمشاهير، أمثال تشارلز ديكنز،
sought to change these dire conditions and help reform the prisoners.
إلى السعي لتغيير هذه الظروف القاسية والمساعدة في تقويم السجناء.
When their movement succeeded,
عندما نجحت حركتهم،
entire prisons were remodeled and new forms of rehabilitation,
تمت إعادة تشكيل السجون بأكملها وأساليب إعادة تأهيل جديدة،
such as the treadmill, were introduced.
كإدخال المشايات في العملية.
Here's how the original version,
وهنا سنعرف كيف تعمل النسخة الأصلية
invented in 1818 by English engineer Sir William Cubitt, worked.
التي اخترعت عام 1818 من قبل المهندس الإنجليزي السير "وليام كيوبيت".
Prisoners stepped on 24 spokes of a large paddle wheel.
داس السجناء على 24 مجدافٍ لعجلة تجديف كبيرة.
As the wheel turned,
كلما تدور العجلة،
the prisoner was forced to keep stepping up or risk falling off,
يضطر السجين للحفاظ على تسارع متزايد أو يخاطر بالسقوط.
similar to modern stepper machines.
على غرار آلات المشي الحديثة.
Meanwhile, the rotation made gears pump out water,
وفي الوقت نفسه،فإن دوران التروس يسبب ضخ الماء،
crush grain,
و سحق الحبوب،
or power mills,
أو تزويد المطاحن بالطاقة،
which is where the name "treadmill" originated.
وهذا أصل اسم (المشايات) "طواحين الدوس".
These devices were seen as a fantastic way of whipping prisoners into shape,
كانت هذه الأجهزة تعتبر وسيلة رائعة لتهذيب السجناء،
and that added benefit of powering mills
كما أن فائدتها الإضافية المتمثلة في تزويد المطاحن بالطاقة،
helped to rebuild a British economy decimated by the Napoleonic Wars.
ساعدت في إعادة بناء الاقتصاد البريطاني الذي دمرته الحروب النابليونية.
It was a win for all concerned, except the prisoners.
كان فوزا لجميع المعنيين، باستثناء السجناء.
It's estimated that, on average,
وتشير التقديرات إلى أنه، بمعدل متوسط،
prisoners spent six or so hours a day on treadmills,
كان السجناء يقضون ست ساعات أو ما يقاربها في اليوم على هذه الآلات،
the equivalent of climbing 5,000 to 14,000 feet.
أي ما يعادل تسلق 5000 إلى 14،000 قدم.
14,000 feet is roughly Mount Everest's halfway point.
14،000 قدم هي تقريبا منتصف الطريق إلى قمة جبل ايفرست.
Imagine doing that five days a week with little food.
تخيل القيام بذلك خمسة أيامٍ في الأسبوع مع وجود القليل من الطعام.
Cubitt's idea quickly spread across the British Empire and America.
فكرة "كيوبيت" سرعان ما انتشرت في جميع أنحاء الإمبراطورية البريطانية وأمريكا.
Within a decade of its creation,
خلال عقد واحد من إنشائها،
over 50 English prisons boasted a treadmill,
فإن أكثر من خمسين سجنًا انكليزيًا تباهوا بامتلاك تلك الآلات.
and America, a similar amount.
وعدد مماثل لذلك في أمريكا.
Unsurprisingly, the exertion combined with poor nutrition
وليس من المستغرب، جراء الجهد المبذول مقرونًا بسوء التغذية،
saw many prisoners suffer breakdowns and injuries,
رؤية العديد من السجناء يعانون من الانهيارات والإصابات،
not that prison guards seemed to care.
ولا يبدو أن حراس السجون اهتموا بالأمر.
In 1824, New York prison guard James Hardie credited the device
في عام 1824، حارس سجن نيويورك "جيمس هاردي" أعطى الفضل للآلة
with taming his more boisterous inmates, writing that
وذلك بتطويع أكثر سجناءه صخبًا، وكتب أن
the "monotonous steadiness, and not its severity...constitutes its terror,"
"ثباتها الرتيب، وليست شدتها .. هو ما يمثل إرهابها،"
a quote many still agree with.
و هو اقتباسٌ لا يزال الكثيرون يوافقون عليه.
And treadmills lasted in England until the late 19th century,
واستمرت المشايات في إنجلترا حتى أواخر القرن التاسع عشر،
when they were banned for being excessively cruel
عندما مُنعت لكونها قاسية بشكل مفرط،
under the Prison's Act of 1898.
بموجب قانون السجون عام 1898.
But of course the torture device returned with a vengeance,
ولكن بالطبع عاد جهاز التعذيب هذا مع الانتقام،
this time targeting the unsuspecting public.
مستهدفًا هذه المرة الأناس الآمنين.
In 1911, a treadmill patent was registered in the U.S.,
في عام 1911، تم تسجيل براءة اختراع "المشّاية" في الولايات المتحدة،
and by 1952, the forerunner for today's modern treadmill had been created.
وفي العام 1952، تم إتخاذ الشكل الحالي للآلة العصرية التي نراها اليوم.
When the jogging craze hit the U.S. in the 1970s,
عندما ضرب جنون الركض الولايات المتحدة في سبعينات القرن الماضي،
the treadmill was thrust back into the limelight
عادت آلة المشي هذه مجددًا تحت الأضواء،
as an easy and convenient way to improve aerobic fitness,
باعتبارها وسيلة سهلة ومريحة لتحسين اللياقة البدنية،
and lose unwanted pounds,
وفقدان الوزن غير المرغوب به،
which, to be fair, it's pretty good at doing.
والتي، و لنكون منصفين، هي جيدة جدا للقيام بها.
And the machine has maintained its popularity since.
وقد حافظت الآلة على شعبيتها منذ ذلك الحين.
So the next time you voluntarily subject yourself to what was once
لذا في المرّة القادمة التي ستعرض بها نفسك طواعيةً إلى ما كان مرّة
a cruel and unusual punishment,
عقوبة قاسية وغير اعتيادية،
just be glad you can control when you'll hop off.
كن مبتهجًا لكونك تتحكم بالوقت الذي سوف ستنزل عنها.